this painting will be auctioned, see the link in the description
We had some snow this night.
It's melting off pretty quickly.
About 10, 15cm or so.
Yeah.
It's a beautiful day.
I'm on my own this week.
Ela is off in town
to do things for herself.
I'm going on a road trip
to Carrara,
which is a place where you can get marble.
I have some ideas for the kitchen
top here in the second cabin.
And also for the vanity in the bathroom
downstairs.
To do it with marble.
Not a job that I will do any time soon.
Because first the workshop
needs to be finished. And,
First, I'll do the roof of this cabin.
But I have a contact in Carrara, which can help me,
show me around some places. And,
see what's there to find.
First I'll work on the roof,
which has to be finished.
Another layer of stone.
And probably preparing the boards
for the sides so I can finish the roof.
And then, tomorrow I'm going to go on the road
Yeah.
Yea, so we could do this in the evening?
Or end of the afternoon
I think one of the best spots
is here
because, like, you're kind of,
some bridges that make a crossing
there are lots of quarries up here.
Yeah.
Sounds good.
Yeah. So it's.
I think it's a really good spot,
but also, yeah, up here is more
they are more hidden.
From the road.
That quarry is about...
three different roads
that go to the quarries.
So there is Torarno
this small little town.
And then there is,
Right. There are other quarries here.
So there are three valleys and then... so three big valleys
And then there are more, because
most of it is happening here, right?
Yeah. All the white are quarries.
These are quarry roads?  Yes.
I thought this one.
And the auto road.
This here is going more behind isn't it.
Exactly.
it goes... it’s like 30 minutes
40, 30 minutes
to go up
So, here and, yeah,
there is a really good, nice view
to all the quarries
Yeah.
I guess to be a student here, it’s a cool place
historic place, a lot going on
big blocks of marble
So all the way down to the valley.
that's...
So there were no roads at all
before that, or?
Yeah, kind of... but, they had roads
Yeah. small roads
Mostly made for. Yeah for carrying
And this is the road where we were before
oh cows..!
It's crazy there.
Yeah. big blocks
one block.
Hold down to the,
all down to the...
where did this have to go?
Because Mussolini was in Rome, or Milan?
Yeah, in Rome, they made a big monument
from that block.
not from this
It's just a small block.
But, usually they...
that's what they carry
blocks every time.
So you can see.
Wow. But.
And it's still there that the monument, or not?
In Rome? I think so yea
But that they carried it
to the port. to the harbour
and then on a boat
Not the cows bring it to Rome, haha
Cement or lime
I don't even know the English word
Beautiful, is this a personal project?
no it’s for a designer
Oh, it's like, sort of a cup or a bowl
Yeah.
It stands
sorry
like that.
Yea, wow. Beautiful
If you want to make the
photo, also?
the video is....
so this is the bookmatch of this
Hey, Lady!
I'll have some chicken bones
for you later.
Wow, this is a lot faster
upgraded the saw
This is a track saw
it's corded so it’s much more powerful
than this one
I’ve been using it for five years,
but for,
making these longer rip cuts in hardwood...
If you remember the rain gutters
it took forever with this
because it's battery powered,
and it needs a bit more.
So corded is better.
And this is the track saw
but I'm still waiting for the track.
So that to make like
perfectly straight cuts.
But I needed the longer one, so.
will arrive, next week I'll flip.
So that's a great upgrade.
A good feeling!
having the scaffolding down,
seeing everything for the first time.
Roof is finished.
So I have to put the boards on next week
on both sides.
And then it’s done
and then rain gutters....
I'll probably do that much later
when the building is waterproof.
I have to make doors, windows...
first close off the walls here
on the underneath the roof on this side.
So there’s a bit of stone work to be done.
It was a nice trip to Carrara
A little holiday.
It's a beautiful drive down Liguria.
You reach Genoa,
and then you're at the Mediterranean Sea.
beautiful, sunny days.
And I went off the toll road
a few times
to see the countryside. It goes very slow
because the roads go...
The hills are very steep
there, but it's incredibly beautiful.
Then you reach Carrara, which is just in Tuscany.
It's about 3.5 hours from here.
But with Fabio, who's...
You might have seen him in the videos
here.
He was helping us in October,
when we were carrying the beams
up as part of the team
And, he studied there,
so he's well-connected.
So he invited me and,
introduced me to some artists and sculptors.
I'll share a link of their art collective
in the in the description.
It's interesting
to see how it works with marble.
I mean, I've got some experience with
Stone now here, but it's quite different.
The Luserna stone...
which is this stone, it's
much harder and more brittle.
So it's more difficult
to cut, easier to hammer.
So here it's just used for
structural purposes, like roofs and walls.
But marble obviously is used
for so many other things.
And Carrara, it's
where it's at, you know, it's where
I'm not sure
if most of the marble comes from there,
but historically it does.
Michelangelo's David,
the block of marble, for example,
comes from there.
So there was a lot of history
interesting to learn about it. And,
interesting to meet the people, stayed in hotel, everything is made of marble.
Very beautiful.
I'm looking forward to, to work with it,
although I have no experience, I have to learn everything, but it's a bit easier
to work with this stone,
so that's probably
a job for, what, next year or so?
Because it's really the last job
I will do on the kitchen
and the bathroom.
So yeah,
sun's coming through again.
Beautiful week.
It's not spring yet.
It's going to snow again.
I think tomorrow, and tonight
Here it’s still a lot of snow
from all the snow
that was swept off the roof during winter.
So that will take a while before it's
gone.
But, yeah, another cold week.
And then I think slowly
things will be warming up.